<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://ali-alkhatib.com//</id>
  <title>Ali Alkhatib</title>
  <updated>2014-10-06T07:38:23-07:00</updated>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://ali-alkhatib.com/"/>
  <link rel="self" href="http://ali-alkhatib.com/blog.xml"/>
  <author>
    <name>Ali Alkhatib</name>
    <uri>http://ali-alkhatib.com/</uri>
  </author>
  
  
  <entry>
    
    <id>http://ali-alkhatib.com/blog/online-labor-markets-and-the-failure-to-compete.html</id>
    
    <title type="html">Online labor markets and the failure to compete</title>
    <updated>2014-09-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://ali-alkhatib.com/blog/online-labor-markets-and-the-failure-to-compete.html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Over the past several months I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a project involving &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mturk.com&quot;&gt;Amazon Mechanical Turk&lt;/a&gt; (henceforth AMT), a fascinating online labor market for &amp;ldquo;micro-labor&amp;rdquo;. Some researchers have done the whole &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~jbigham/posts/2014/half-workday-as-turker.html&quot;&gt;crash course ethnographic thing&lt;/a&gt;, but for the most part research of online labor has taken a look from a step back (as &lt;a href=&quot;http://john-joseph-horton.com/papers/online_labor_markets.pdf&quot;&gt;Horton&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=1869100&quot;&gt;Silberman et al.&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://john-joseph-horton.com/papers/futureofcrowdwork-cscw2013.pdf&quot;&gt;others&lt;/a&gt; have done).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project, resulting in a website called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wearedynamo.org/&quot;&gt;Dynamo&lt;/a&gt;, has been intense, but enlightening. It&amp;rsquo;s been a unique process going from iterating on a serious web project to thinking at a high level about the social significance of our design decisions and how to evoke the outcomes we want. In this case, the outcome we wanted was &amp;ldquo;collective action&amp;rdquo;. By this I mean that we wanted to bring people together specifically to accomplish &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;. In some sense, we had no agenda because of this. In another sense, we absolutely had an ulterior motive, and a forceful one at that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our initial fieldwork results suggested that there were serious problems with AMT that desperately called for some collective action of some sort. Whether that be a union of Turkers, a labor strike, a letter-writing campaign, or whatever, we got the impression that Turkers were calling for &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;. Before you get ahead of yourself, I&amp;rsquo;ll present a qualified view, not entirely dismissing this preconception but neither totally embracing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first round of fieldwork suggested &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; strongly that there was a single actor in the AMT marketplace who was poisoning the well in some sense by putting out what Turkers call &lt;a href=&quot;#pennyHIT&quot;&gt;penny HITs&lt;/a&gt;. By itself, in a totally naive environment, this really wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be that big a deal; he pays too little, some people aren&amp;rsquo;t willing to do that much work for $0.25, but some people &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt;, so those that are willing will do his work and those that are not will go do other tasks. Everyone wins (except the Turkers who do his work, but they&amp;rsquo;re happy digging their grave. Or so the argument goes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not quite so. In practice, these &lt;a href=&quot;#HIT&quot;&gt;HITs&lt;/a&gt; and others set a standard &amp;ndash; a norm &amp;ndash; in the marketplace, so that even academic researchers (whom we generally regard as being paragons of ethical behavior, justified or not) were paying workers poorly; the market had become one for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iei.liu.se/nek/730g83/artiklar/1.328833/AkerlofMarketforLemons.pdf&quot;&gt;lemons&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we thought that a demonstration for this and other HIT requesters would give them the necessary push to show that&lt;br /&gt;
1. Turkers are not to be trifled with&lt;br /&gt;
2. Turkers are human beings&lt;br /&gt;
3. Turkers ought to be treated with basic respect and decency&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our plan was to help Turkers stage a labor protest; they would do &lt;em&gt;bad&lt;/em&gt; work intentionally, in a systematically defined way, so that all of the work a requester solicited would be unusable. This was the idea &lt;strong&gt;we&lt;/strong&gt; came up with, bridging some gaps between online and offline labor markets, dynamics, and politics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turkers were not enthusiastic with our idea. In fact, more accurately, they hated it with a passion I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen in a while. So we went back to the drawing board for a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, we realized that we didn&amp;rsquo;t know anything (one could argue that I should&amp;rsquo;ve known this for quite a while, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t know anything; also, I digress), so we figured that we should just let Turkers come up with their own actions. While this was on one hand more practical than designing our own perfect campaign, it was more importantly a truer representation of homegrown &lt;strong&gt;collective action&lt;/strong&gt;, which was becoming the focal point of our research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t bore you with many more details &amp;ndash; and frankly I find more and more that I don&amp;rsquo;t have time for them &amp;ndash; but of note we have a few things which I think are worth patting ourselves on the back:&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ndash; We came up with a guideline of ethical research protocols developed by the community to which these guidelines are relevant.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ndash; We got some serious buy-in from researchers in the HCI community (including, but not limited to, Don Norman of UCSD).&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ndash; We learned a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; about online workers, online labor markets, and online communities in general. I genuinely feel more confident about community design and building now than I ever did before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve submitted our paper to a conference (deadline was on my birthday, so that was fun&amp;hellip;), I&amp;rsquo;m moving on to my own project, of my own design, with no conference deadline in immediate sight: I&amp;rsquo;m going to try and build a new type of online labor marketplace, where the workers set their own rules and norms, including things like minimum wage, what sorts of work they&amp;rsquo;ll do, and other factors. My hope is that this will return some of the leverage Amazon puts in the requester&amp;rsquo;s hands back to the workers themselves. Ideally, there should be as equal a playing field as possible, rather than one that&amp;rsquo;s exploitative of workers. If this all pans out, it just might be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Glossary:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;HIT&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;HIT: Human Intelligence Task (essentially, a work task) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;pennyHIT&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;penny HIT: A cheap HIT, often one not worth the time to complete it. For example, a HIT that pays $1 for 5 minutes of work does not seem to be considered a &amp;ldquo;penny HIT&amp;rdquo;, but a $1 HIT that takes 10 or 20 minutes to complete would fall squarely into &amp;ldquo;penny HIT&amp;rdquo; category&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Over the past several months I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a project involving [Amazon Mechanical Turk][1] (henceforth AMT), a fascinating online labor market for &amp;ldquo;micro-labor&amp;rdquo;. Some researchers have done the whole [crash course ethnographic thing][2], but for the most part research of online labor has taken a look from a step back (as [Horton][3], [Silberman et al.][4], and [others][5] have done).&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <id>http://ali-alkhatib.com/blog/qs-thesis-finally.html</id>
    
    <title type="html">QS Thesis (finally)</title>
    <updated>2014-07-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://ali-alkhatib.com/blog/qs-thesis-finally.html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After getting some feedback from my advisor I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure I&amp;rsquo;m ready to put this out there&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a look at my &lt;a href=&quot;http://ali-alkhatib.com/presentations/QSThesisFinal.pdf&quot;&gt;Quantified Self thesis&lt;/a&gt;, which I completed as part of the honors program in Anthropology at UC Irvine&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After getting some feedback from my advisor I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure I&amp;rsquo;m ready to put this out there&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <id>http://ali-alkhatib.com/blog/quantified-self-2.html</id>
    
    <title type="html">Quantified Self</title>
    <updated>2014-06-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://ali-alkhatib.com/blog/quantified-self-2.html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently finished my honors thesis on Quantified Self. Or more accurately, I ran out of time.&lt;br /&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ll post it and link here when I get feedback from my advisor.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently finished my honors thesis on Quantified Self. Or more accurately, I ran out of time.&lt;br /&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ll post it and link here when I get feedback from my advisor.&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <id>http://ali-alkhatib.com/blog/quantified-self.html</id>
    
    <title type="html">Quantified Self</title>
    <updated>2014-05-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://ali-alkhatib.com/blog/quantified-self.html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the past year I&amp;rsquo;ve been studying the culture of Quantified Self. Last weekend I gave a talk on the research at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.urop.uci.edu/symposium.html&quot;&gt;Undergraduate Research Opportunities Program Symposium&lt;/a&gt;, and in the spirit of QS culture (especially with regard to open access to data, etc&amp;hellip;) I thought I&amp;rsquo;d post the presentation. The PowerPoint is &lt;a href=&quot;/presentations/QS.ppt&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (warning: 12.9 MB). Alternatively, you can download a PDF &lt;a href=&quot;/presentations/QS.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (9.8 MB).&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the past year I&amp;rsquo;ve been studying the culture of Quantified Self. Last weekend I gave a talk on the research at the [Undergraduate Research Opportunities Program Symposium][1], and in the spirit of QS culture (especially with regard to open access to data, etc&amp;hellip;) I thought I&amp;rsquo;d post the presentation. The PowerPoint is [here][2] (warning: 12.9 MB). Alternatively, you can download a PDF [here][3] (9.8 MB).&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <id>http://ali-alkhatib.com/blog/130.html</id>
    
    <title type="html">Oh right, this exists</title>
    <updated>2014-04-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://ali-alkhatib.com/blog/130.html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My last substantive post was about how broken graduate school applications are, so I think it makes sense that my next post would be about graduate schools again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the better part of the last few months worrying that my statements of purpose wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be well-received. Not because I worried that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t written my SoPs well, or because my research wasn&amp;rsquo;t interesting (well, to me anyway), but because I was afraid that I had been on the fence for too long, so committed to interdisciplinary studies that I had forfeited my stake in both social sciences and computer science. I was afraid that I was too quantitative for qualitative fields (like Anthropology) and too qualitative for quantitative fields (like Computer Science).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several months ago I got a call from Stanford. I went for a visit, and I&amp;rsquo;ve signed the proverbial papers; I&amp;rsquo;ll be joining Stanford&amp;rsquo;s Computer Science program to pursue a PhD. Specifically, I&amp;rsquo;ll be studying digital cultures and working in the HCI group (after the initial year of rotations).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still settling into the bizarre turn of events, especially the lingering misgivings I&amp;rsquo;ve had about ultimately leaving the social sciences, which got me into academia in the first place (and where I feel my research interests belong), but after speaking with Michael Bernstein, Jure Leskovec, Dan Jurafsky, Chris Re, and others, I really can&amp;rsquo;t imagine being anywhere but Stanford and in Computer Science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It just happens to be really convenient that the clout associated with CS at Stanford affords me immense credibility in some circles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More updates eventually. I&amp;rsquo;m trying to stay above the day-to-day errands of housing lotteries and personal stuff because I kind of assume nobody reading this is interested. My next unprompted post will &lt;em&gt;probably&lt;/em&gt; be about Quantified Self, the undergraduate thesis I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on for the honors Anthro program at UC Irvine, for which Dr. Boellstorff has been advising me.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My last substantive post was about how broken graduate school applications are, so I think it makes sense that my next post would be about graduate schools again.&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
